Hudson River Conservation Society, Inc. Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Hudson River Conservation Society, Inc. Collection
1930 - 1980
NPkMC-222-095
24 Linear Feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
The Hudson River Conservation Society, Inc.
The Hudson River Conservation Society was founded in 1936 in order to preserve and protect scenic and historic landmarks in the Hudson Valley and seek regulation when necessary to achieve this. The Hudson River Conservation Society Collection documents the history and continued efforts of the Society as a non-profit agency, fighting for the conservation and protection of the Hudson River, its surroundings, and its environment. The Hudson River Conservation Society collection consists of correspondence, office records, reports, memoranda, newsletters, brochures, maps, newspaper clippings, press releases, opinion polls, financial records, scrapbooks, photographs, books, and other printed material.
Related Collections
Hudson River Environmental Society Library
Collection Overview
The collection consists of correspondence, office records, reports, memoranda, newsletters, brochures, maps, newspaper clippings, press releases, opinion polls, financial records, scrapbooks, photographs, books, and other printed material related to the founding and continuing work of the Hudson River Conservation Society as a private, non-profit, watchdog agency of the Hudson River Valley and its environment. The collection is maintained in its original order.
Acquisitions Information
The Hudson River Conservation Society Collection was given to the Marist College Library by the F.D.R. Library, where it was donated by John Winthrop Aldrich on behalf of the Hudson River Conservation Society.
Historical Note
The Hudson River Conservation Society was incorporated September 3, 1936 in order to protect and maintain the beauties of the Hudson Valley, preserve its scenic and historic landmarks, eliminate pollution, develop recreational values, cooperate with industry and seek regulation where necessary to help achieve these aims, make a continuing survey of the river and its valley, and to receive funds to do so. In response to destructive quarrying at High Tor and Mount Taurus, the Hudson River Conservation Society was organized on April 15, 1936. Upon the creation of the Society, William Church Osborn served as President, with John Ross Delafield as Vice-President, Louis V. Ledoux as Treasurer and Margaret Gillmore as Secretary. Under their leadership, the Society sponsored two pieces of legislation; one created the Hudson Valley Commission to make a survey of the river and recommend a plan for its development and protection and the other permitted the State Conservation Commissioner to accept gifts of historic or scenic sites of interest.
The Hudson River Conservation Society played an active role in the preservation of historic and scenic sites in the Hudson Valley. Several purchases of land were made including the 1936 purchase of the north slope of Breakneck Mountain, which was eventually given to the Taconic State Park Commission, the Storm King section on the north face of Anthony’s Nose, which was eventually given to the American Scenic and Historic Preservation Society, and the 1943 purchase of High Tor which was eventually handed over to the Palisades Park Commission. The publication of Historic Houses of the Hudson Valley was sponsored by the Society. Also, under the leadership of the Society, zoning regulations were enforced in Clarkstown in order to prevent quarrying by New York Trap Rock. The Hudson River Conservation Society also discouraged the building of the Storm King By-Pass, the Hudson River Tourway and the New York-New Jersey Turnpike-Thruway Link and supported the Palisades Interstate Parkway and the development of the Taconic State Parkway. The Society has been involved in developing marinas, watershed projects, sewage systems, conservation courses at colleges, backing legislation that protects the river and surrounding areas, and increasing awareness of these issues.
Restrictions to Access
There are no restrictions on this collection
Collection is arranged into two series: 1. Hudson River Conservation Society Files, and 2. Scrapbooks
Materials maintain original order.
- 1. Hudson River Conservation Society Files, 1939 - 1959; 1; 19 linear feet 1 - 55 1 - 177
  A collection of materials gathered by the Hudson River Conservation Society, dealing with their own activities to preserve the Hudson River.
  Original Order (alphabetical)
  - A (Folder 1, Box 1)
  - Action for Preservation and Conservation of the North Shore of Long Island, Inc. (Folder 2, Box 1)
  - Addresses and Printed Material (Folder 3, Box 1)
  - Adirondack Hudson River Association (Folder 4, Box 1)
  - Adirondack Moose River Project (Folder 5, Box 1)
  - Adirondack Mountain Club (Folder 6, Box 1)
  - Adirondack Museum, Blue Mountain Lake, N.Y. (Folder 7, Box 1)
  - Adirondack Park (Folder 8, Box 1)
  - Adirondack Park Agency (Folder 9, Box 1)
  - Air Pollution (Folder 10, Box 1)
  - Air Pollution - Auto Exhaust (Folder 11, Box 1)
  - Air Pollution - Printed Materials (Folder 12, Box 2)
  - Air Pollution Control Board (Folder 13, Box 2)
  - Albany Area Correspondence (Folder 14, Box 2)
  - Albany Chapter (Folder 15, Box 2)
  - Albany Chapter - Upper Hudson Project-Adirondack Park Association (Folder 16, Box 2)
  - Albany-Glens Falls Area: HUDSON HERALD (Folder 17, Box 2)
  - Albany Institute of History and Art (Folder 18, Box 2)
  - Albany Membership Prospect List (Folder 19, Box 2)
  - Albany-Troy Area, Organizational Meetings (Folder 20, Box 2)
  - Albany-Troy Area, Publicity (Folder 21, Box 2)
  - Albright, Horace M. (Folder 22, Box 2)
  - Aldrich, Winthrop (Folder 23, Box 2)
  - Alliger, Fanny (Folder 24, Box 2)
  - Along the Hudson - Katzenbach and Warren, Inc. (Folder 25, Box 2)
  - American Association of University Women (Folder 26, Box 2)
  - American Craftsmen’s Educational Council (Folder 27, Box 2)
  - American Geographical Society (Folder 28, Box 2)
  - American Scenic and Historic Preservation Society (Folder 29, Box 2)
  - Amerling, Robert (Folder 30, Box 2)
  - Annual Meetings 1937 - 1944 (Folder 31, Box 3)
  - Annual Meeting 1945 (Folder 32, Box 3)
  - Annual Meeting 1946 (Folder 33, Box 3)
  - Annual Meeting 1947 (Folder 34, Box 3)
  - Annual Meeting 1948 (Folder 35, Box 3)
  - Annual Meeting 1949 (Folder 36, Box 3)
  - Annual Meeting 1950 (Folder 37, Box 3)
  - Annual Meeting 1951 (Folder 38, Box 3)
  - Annual Meeting 1952 (Folder 39, Box 3)
  - Annual Meeting 1953 (Folder 40, Box 3)
  - Annual Meeting 1954 (Folder 41, Box 3)
  - Annual Meetings 1955 - 1958 (Folder 42, Box 4)
  - Annual Meetings 1959 - 1968 (Folder 43, Box 4)
  - Annual Meeting 1970 (Folder 44, Box 4)
  - Annual Meeting 1971 (Folder 45, Box 4)
  - Annual Meeting 1972 (Folder 46, Box 4)
  - Annual Meeting 1974 (Folder 47, Box 4)
  - Annual Meeting 1975 (Folder 48, Box 4)
  - Annual Meeting 1976 (Folder 49, Box 4)
  - Annual Meeting 1977 (Folder 50, Box 4)
  - Annual Meeting 1978 (Folder 51, Box 4)
  - Annual Meeting Reports (Folder 52, Box 4)
  - Annual Report 1937 (Folder 53, Box 4)
  - Annual Report 1938 (Folder 54, Box 4)
  - Annual Report 1939 (Folder 55, Box 4)
  - Annual Report 1940 (Folder 56, Box 4)
  - Annual Report 1944 - 1945 (Folder 57, Box 4)
  - Anti-Pollution League (Folder 58, Box 4)
  - Appalachian Highlands Association, Inc. (Folder 59, Box 4)
  - Articles (Folder 60, Box 5)
  - Atlantic Highlands Municipal Harbor (Folder 61, Box 5)
  - Atomic Energy Commission (Folder 62, Box 5)
  - Audubon House (Folder 63, Box 5)
  - B (Folder 64, Box 5)
  - Balmville Tree (Folder 65, Box 5)
  - Bannerman’s Island (Folder 66, Box 5)
  - Beacon - Fishkill Branch (Folder 67, Box 5)
  - Beacon - Founder’s Fund Award (Folder 68, Box 5)
  - Bibliography of the Hudson River (Folder 69, Box 5)
  - Billboard Abatement (Folder 70, Box 5)
  - Black Rock Forest Committee (Folder 71, Box 5)
  - Board of Directors 1938 (Folder 72, Box 5)
  - Board of Directors 1939 (Folder 73, Box 5)
  - Board of Directors 1940 (Folder 74, Box 5)
  - Board of Directors 1941 (Folder 75, Box 5)
  - Board of Directors 1942 (Folder 76, Box 5)
  - Board of Directors 1943 (Folder 77, Box 5)
  - Board of Directors 1945 (Folder 78, Box 5)
  - Board of Directors 1946 (Folder 79, Box 5)
  - Board of Directors 1947 (Folder 80, Box 5)
  - Board of Directors 1948 (Folder 81, Box 5)
  - Board of Directors 1949 (Folder 82, Box 5)
  - Board of Directors 1950 (Folder 83, Box 6)
  - Board of Directors 1951 (Folder 84, Box 6)
  - Board of Directors 1952 (Folder 85, Box 6)
  - Board of Directors 1953 (Folder 86, Box 6)
  - Board of Directors 1954 (Folder 87, Box 6)
  - Board of Directors 1955 (Folder 88, Box 6)
  - Board of Directors 1956 (Folder 89, Box 6)
  - Board of Directors 1957 (Folder 90, Box 6)
  - Board of Directors 1958 (Folder 91, Box 6)
  - Board of Directors 1959 (Folder 92, Box 6)
  - Board of Directors 1960 (Folder 93, Box 6)
  - Board of Directors 1961 (Folder 94, Box 6)
  - Board of Directors 1962 (Folder 95, Box 6)
  - Board of Directors 1963 (Folder 96, Box 6)
  - Board of Directors 1964 (Folder 97, Box 6)
  - Board of Directors 1965 (Folder 98, Box 6)
  - Board of Directors 1966 (Folder 99, Box 7)
  - Board of Directors 1967 (Folder 100, Box 7)
  - Board of Directors 1968 (Folder 101, Box 7)
  - Board of Directors 1970 (Folder 102, Box 7)
  - Board of Directors 1971 (Folder 103, Box 7)
  - Board of Directors 1972 (Folder 104, Box 7)
  - Board of Directors 1973 (Folder 105, Box 7)
  - Board of Directors 1974 (Folder 106, Box 7)
  - Board of Directors 1975 (Folder 107, Box 7)
  - Board of Directors 1976 (Folder 108, Box 7)
  - Board of Directors 1977 (Folder 109, Box 7)
  - Board of Directors 1978 (Folder 110, Box 7)
  - Board of Directors - Advisory Committee 1961 - 1968 (Folder 111, Box 7)
  - Board of Directors - Committees of the Board (Folder 112, Box 7)
  - Board of Directors - Executive Committee (Folder 113, Box 7)
  - Boating Almanac 1965 (Folder 114, Box 7)
  - Booklets and Brochures (Folder 115, Box 7)
  - Boscobel (Folder 116, Box 7)
  - Branch Chairmen Meetings (Folder 117, Box 8)
  - Branches in Kingston, Catskill and Saugerties (Folder 118, Box 8)
  - Brandywine Valley Association (Folder 119, Box 8)
  - Break-through to the River: A Plan for Yonkers to Peekskill (Folder 120, Box 8)
  - Buffalo Museum of Science (Folder 121, Box 8)
  - C (Folder 122, Box 8)
  - Campfire Club of America (Folder 123, Box 8)
  - The Capitol Area (Folder 124, Box 8)
  - Carmer, Carl (Folder 125, Box 8)
  - Catskill Cement Plants (Folder 126, Box 8)
  - Center for Coordinated Environmental Living (Folder 127, Box 8)
  - Center for the Hudson River Valley (Folder 128, Box 8)
  - Central Hudson Gas and Electric Corporation (Folder 129, Box 8)
  - Central Hudson Gas and Electric Corporation - Interstate 84 (Folder 130, Box 8)
  - Certificate of Incorporation, Constitution and By- Laws (Folder 131, Box 8)
  - Chapman, Conrad (Folder 132, Box 8)
  - Citizen’s Committee for the Hudson River (Folder 133, Box 8)
  - Citizen’s Committee for the Outdoor Recreation Resources Commission (Folder 134, Box 8)
  - Citizens Committee for the Protection of the Environment (Folder 135, Box 9)
  - Citizens Committee on Natural Resources (Folder 136, Box 9)
  - Clark, Mrs. LeRoy (Garden Club of America) (Folder 137, Box 9)
  - Clean Air Act of 1970 (Folder 138, Box 9)
  - Clean Waters (Folder 139, Box 9)
  - Clippings 1937 - 1972 (Folder 140, Box 9)
  - Coast Guard (Folder 141, Box 9)
  - Coastal Zone Management Program (Folder 142, Box 9)
  - Cold Spring - Founder’s Fund Award (Folder 143, Box 9)
  - Columbia County Branch (Folder 144, Box 9)
  - Committee for the New York-Montreal Seaway (Folder 145, Box 9)
  - Committee to Preserve the National Capitol (Folder 146, Box 9)
  - Commonwealth Fund (Folder 147, Box 9)
  - Community Garden Club, Marlborough-on-Hudson (Folder 148, Box 9)
  - Concerned Citizens of Highland (Folder 149, Box 9)
  - Conference in the Matter of the Pollution of the Interstate Waters of the Hudson River…,1967 (Folder 150, Box 9)
  - Conference on Natural Beauty, 1966 (Folder 151, Box 10)
  - Conrad Chapman Award for the Garrison Waterfront (Folder 152, Box 10)
  - Conservation (Folder 153, Box 10)
  - Conservation Education (Folder 154, Box 10)
  - Conservation Forum in New York State (Folder 155, Box 10)
  - Conservation Foundation (Folder 156, Box 10)
  - Conservation League (Folder 157, Box 10)
  - Conservation Work in Schools Along the Hudson (Folder 158, Box 10)
  - Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc. 1957 - 1963 (Folder 159, Box 11)
  - Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc. 1964 (Folder 160, Box 11)
  - Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc. 1965 (Folder 161, Box 11)
  - Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc. 1966 - 1967 (Folder 162, Box 11)
  - Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc. Photographs and Brochures (Folder 163, Box 12)
  - Con Ed Proposed Transmission Line Routes 1 and 1a (Folder 164, Box 12)
  - Con Ed Proposed Transmission Line Routes 2 and 3 (Folder 165, Box 12)
  - Con Ed Proposed Transmission Routes 2 - 4 and Modifications (Folder 166, Box 12)
  - Constitution Committee (Folder 167, Box 12)
  - Constitution Island Association (Folder 168, Box 12)
  - Constitutional Convention (Folder 169, Box 13)
  - Constitutional Council for Forest Preserves (Folder 170, Box 13)
  - Corning, Mrs. Erastus II (Folder 171, Box 13)
  - Cornish Property (Folder 172, Box 13)
  - Cornu, Theodore J. (Folder 173, Box 13)
  - Cornwall-on-Hudson Branch (Folder 174, Box 13)
  - Cornwall - Founder’s Fund Award (Folder 175, Box 13)
  - Correspondence Index (Folder 176, Box 13)
  - Cortland&Conservation Society (Folder 177, Box 13)
  - Croton - Founder’s Fund Award (Folder 178, Box 13)
  - Croton Marsh Dumping (Folder 179, Box 13)
  - Croton Point Yacht Basin (Folder 180, Box 13)
  - Cruger’s Island (Folder 181, Box 13)
  - Cruise Guidebooks (Folder 182, Box 13)
  - D (Folder 183, Box 13)
  - Dalliba, Mrs. William Swift (Folder 184, Box 13)
  - Dams on the Upper Hudson (Folder 185, Box 14)
  - Dappert, Anselmo F. (Folder 186, Box 14)
  - Decision on the Hudson (Folder 187, Box 14)
  - Delafield, Mrs. John White (Folder 188, Box 14)
  - Delaware River Basin (Folder 189, Box 14)
  - Desmond, Thomas C. (Folder 190, Box 14)
  - Developing and Managing the Water Resources of New York State (Folder 191, Box 14)
  - Dewey, Thomas F. (Folder 192, Box 14)
  - Diorama of the Hudson River Highlands - Founder’s Fund Award (Folder 193, Box 14)
  - Directory of Historical Societies and Agencies (Folder 194, Box 14)
  - Directory of Registered Charitable Organizations (Folder 195, Box 14)
  - Dobbs Ferry Garden Club (Folder 196, Box 14)
  - Dobbs Ferry Woman’s Club (Folder 197, Box 14)
  - Donaldson, Mrs. John W. (Folder 198, Box 14)
  - Drew, Mrs. Marion (Folder 199, Box 14)
  - Dutchess County (Folder 200, Box 14)
  - Dutchess County Data Book 1962 (Folder 201, Box 14)
  - Dutchess County Historical Society (Folder 202, Box 14)
  - Dutchess County Soil and Water Conservation District (Folder 203, Box 14)
  - E (Folder 204, Box 15)
  - Easements (Folder 205, Box 15)
  - Eastern Highlands (Folder 206, Box 15)
  - Eggert, Charles (Folder 207, Box 15)
  - Energy Conservation Strategies (Folder 208, Box 15)
  - Englewood Garden Club (Folder 209, Box 15)
  - Environmental Planning Lobby (Folder 210, Box 15)
  - F (Folder 211, Box 15)
  - Federal Interagency River Basin Committee (Folder 212, Box 15)
  - Federal Power Commission 1966 - 1973 (Folder 213, Box 15)
  - Federal Power Commission Hearings 1966 - 1967 (Folder 214, Box 15)
  - Federal Power Commission Hearings 1968 - 1974 (Folder 215, Box 15)
  - Federated Conservationists of Westchester County, Inc. (Folder 216, Box 15)
  - File Index (Folder 217, Box 15)
  - Financial Matters: Anthony’s Nose (Folder 218, Box 16)
  - Financial Matters: Auditor’s Reports (Folder 219, Box 16)
  - Financial Matters: Bank of New York Statements and Cancelled Checks 1954 (Folder 220, Box 16)
  - Financial Matters: Bank of New York Statements and Cancelled Checks 1955 (Folder 221, Box 16)
  - Financial Matters: Bank of New York Statements and Cancelled Checks 1956 (Folder 222, Box 16)
  - Financial Matters: Bank of New York Statements and Cancelled Checks 1957 (Folder 223, Box 16)
  - Financial Matters: Bank of New York Statements and Cancelled Checks 1958 (Folder 224, Box 16)
  - Financial Matters: Bank of New York Statements and Cancelled Checks 1959 (Folder 225, Box 16)
  - Financial Matters: Bank of New York Statements and Cancelled Checks 1960 (Folder 226, Box 16)
  - Financial Matters: Bank of New York Statements and Cancelled Checks 1961 - 1964 (Folder 227, Box 16)
  - Financial Matters: Bank of New York Checkbook 1956 - 1959 (Folder 228, Box 17)
  - Financial Matters: Bank of New York Checkbook 1959 - 1961 (Folder 229, Box 17)
  - Financial Matters: Bank of New York Correspondence (Folder 230, Box 17)
  - Financial Matters: Clipping Bureau (Folder 231, Box 17)
  - Financial Matters: Connaughton, Howard W. (Folder 232, Box 17)
  - Financial Matters: Contributors - Special Drive 1968 (Folder 233, Box 17)
  - Financial Matters: Donors (Folder 234, Box 17)
  - Financial Matters: Dues Collection (Folder 235, Box 17)
  - Financial Matters: Dues Notes (Folder 236, Box 17)
  - Financial Matters: Executive Director (Folder 237, Box 17)
  - Financial Matters: Expenses (Folder 238, Box 17)
  - Financial Matters: Finances 1936 - 1937 (Folder 239, Box 17)
  - Financial Matters 1970 - 1971 (Folder 240, Box 18)
  - Financial Matters 1972 (Folder 241, Box 18)
  - Financial Matters 1973 (Folder 242, Box 18)
  - Financial Matters 1974 (Folder 243, Box 18)
  - Financial Matters 1975 (Folder 244, Box 18)
  - Financial Matters 1976 (Folder 245, Box 18)
  - Financial Matters 1977 (Folder 246, Box 18)
  - Financial Matters 1978 (Folder 247, Box 18)
  - Financial Matters 1979 (Folder 248, Box 18)
  - Financial Matters: Financial Reports (Folder 249, Box 18)
  - Financial Matters: Financial Statements (Folder 250, Box 18)
  - Financial Matters: Frothingham Trust (Folder 251, Box 19)
  - Financial Matters: Fund Raising (Folder 252, Box 19)
  - Financial Matters: Hudson Herald Fund (Folder 253, Box 19)
  - Financial Matters: Hurdman and Cranstown (Folder 254, Box 19)
  - Financial Matters: IBM Stock (Folder 255, Box 19)
  - Financial Matters: Investments (Folder 256, Box 19)
  - Financial Matters: Land Options and Contributions (Folder 257, Box 19)
  - Financial Matters: Ledger Sheets. See also Oversize Item (Folder 258, Box 19)
  - Financial Matters: Membership (Folder 259, Box 19)
  - Financial Matters: Membership - Dues Book (Folder 260, Box 19)
  - Financial Matters: Minute Book 1936 - 1956 (Folder 261, Box 19)
  - Financial Matters: Minute Book 1937 - 1953 (Folder 262, Box 19)
  - Financial Matters: Minute Book 1956 - 1968 (Folder 263, Box 20)
  - Financial Matters: Minute Book Miscellaneous 1936 - 1968 (Folder 264, Box 20)
  - Financial Matters: New York State Income Tax (Folder 265, Box 20)
  - Financial Matters: New York Telephone Company (Folder 266, Box 20)
  - Financial Matters: Office Receipts and Expenditures (Folder 267, Box 20)
  - Financial Matters: Office Records (Folder 268, Box 20)
  - Financial Matters: Receipted Bills (Folder 269, Box 20)
  - Financial Matters: Seamen’s Bank for Savings (Folder 270, Box 21)
  - Financial Matters: Social Security (Folder 271, Box 21)
  - Financial matters: Treasurer’s Reports (Folder 272, Box 21)
  - Financial Matters: Treasurer’s Reports of Dues Received (Folder 273, Box 21)
  - Financial Matters; Typewriter - Remington Rand, Inc. (Folder 274, Box 21)
  - Financial Matters: Victory Tax and Withholding Tax (Folder 275, Box 21)
  - Financial Matters: Whiting Bequest (Folder 276, Box 21)
  - Fish Kills (Folder 277, Box 22)
  - Fishkill Historical Society Newsletter (Folder 278, Box 22)
  - Flood Control (Folder 279, Box 22)
  - Flower Show Booth 1938 (Folder 280, Box 22)
  - Flower Show Booth 1941 (Folder 281, Box 22)
  - Fluoridation of Public Waters in New York State (Folder 282, Box 22)
  - Focus on the Hudson (Folder 283, Box 22)
  - Forbes Business Service, Inc. (Folder 284, Box 22)
  - Forever Wild (Folder 285, Box 22)
  - Ft. Crailo, Ft. Orange Garden Club, Albany, New York (Folder 286, Box 22)
  - Fortington, Mrs. Harold A. (Folder 287, Box 22)
  - Foundations (Folder 288, Box 22)
  - Founder’s Fund Award - Garden Club of America (Folder 289, Box 22)
  - Founder’s Fund Award - Reports (Folder 290, Box 22)
  - Founder’s Fund Award Committee (Folder 291, Box 22)
  - Frazier, Benjamin (Folder 292, Box 22)
  - Friends of the Earth (Folder 293, Box 22)
  - Friends of the Hudson (Folder 294, Box 22)
  - G (Folder 295, Box 22)
  - Garden Club of America (Folder 296, Box 22)
  - Garden Club of Orange and Dutchess Counties (Folder 297, Box 22)
  - Garden Club of Yorktown (Folder 298, Box 22)
  - Garden Parties for Membership (Folder 299, Box 22)
  - Garrison - Cold Springs, N.Y. (Folder 300, Box 23)
  - Garrison Memorial (Folder 301, Box 23)
  - Gateway Citizens Committee (Folder 302, Box 23)
  - General Council (Folder 303, Box 23)
  - George Island Marsh Fund (Folder 304, Box 23)
  - Germantown Garden Club (Folder 305, Box 23)
  - Gillmore, Margaret (Folder 306, Box 23)
  - Glunt, Mrs. Chester B. (Folder 307, Box 23)
  - Governor’s Council on Natural Beauty - 1966 (Folder 308, Box 23)
  - Green Vlei Swamp, Fishkill (Folder 309, Box 23)
  - Greene County (Folder 310, Box 23)
  - Greene County Chairman (Folder 311, Box 23)
  - Greene County Historical Society (Folder 312, Box 23)
  - Grundy, J. Owen (Folder 313, Box 23)
  - H (Folder 314, Box 23)
  - Hader, Elmer J. (Folder 315, Box 23)
  - Hamilton, Alexander - American Scenic and Historic Preservation Society (Folder 316, Box 24)
  - Hamilton, Alexander (Folder 317, Box 24)
  - Hardy, Ruth Gillette (Folder 318, Box 24)
  - Harriman, Governor Averell (Folder 319, Box 24)
  - Hastings Garden Club (Folder 320, Box 24)
  - Hastings Woman’s Club (Folder 321, Box 24)
  - Health News (Folder 322, Box 24)
  - Hickey, Edward W. (Folder 323, Box 24)
  - High Tor 1942 (Folder 324, Box 24)
  - High Tor 1943 - 1956 (Folder 325, Box 24)
  - High Tor Maps (Folder 326, Box 24)
  - High Tor Plays (Folder 327, Box 25)
  - High Tor Scrapbook (Folder 328, Box 25)
  - Highway (Hudson River Tourway) (Folder 329, Box 25)
  - Historic Books (Folder 330, Box 25)
  - Historic- House Keeping (Folder 331, Box 25)
  - Historic Houses (Folder 332, Box 25)
  - Historic Houses of the Hudson Valley (Folder 333, Box 25)
  - Historic Houses of the Hudson Valley - Costs (Folder 334, Box 25)
  - History of the Hudson River Conservation Society (Folder 335, Box 25)
  - Historic Sites (Folder 336, Box 26)
  - Historic Sites of New York State (Folder 337, Box 26)
  - Historical Committee (Folder 338, Box 26)
  - Holland- America Line (Folder 339, Box 26)
  - Hoppen, William (Folder 340, Box 26)
  - Horticulture and Conservation Day (Folder 341, Box 26)
  - Howard, Norman (Folder 342, Box 26)
  - The Hudson (Folder 343, Box 26)
  - Hudson - Champlain Celebration (Folder 344, Box 26)
  - Hudson - Champlain Committee (Folder 345, Box 26)
  - Hudson - Fulton Celebration (Folder 346, Box 26)
  - Hudson Herald 1964 - 1969 (Folder 347, Box 27)
  - Hudson Herald 1970 - 1979 (Folder 348, Box 27)
  - Hudson Herald- Work (Folder 349, Box 27)
  - Hudson Highlands National Scenic Riverway (Folder 350, Box 27)
  - Hudson Highlands State Park (Folder 351, Box 27)
  - Hudson, New York (Folder 352, Box 27)
  - Hudson River - Art (Folder 353, Box 27)
  - Hudson River - Articles (Folder 354, Box 27)
  - Hudson River - Dredging (Folder 355, Box 27)